#### COATING SCIENTIST

#### Summary

Knowledgeable Operator skilled in production and manufacturing of food and pharmaceutical products. Responsible and hardworking individual with solid work history, who can collaborate well in a team or individually to produce quality work on tight deadlines. Coating Scientist with positive attitude and a commitment to safety, quality, and compliant with FDA and DEA regulations. Hardworking, strong and physically agile manufacturing professional who excels at any assignment given. Experienced manufacturing professional with strong leadership and relationship-building skills.

#### Highlights

- 11 years experience in Production and Manufacturing
- Specialist in weighing, mixing/blending, coating, labeling, and slitting
- Dedication to Product quality
- Strong background in FDA drug safety guidelines
- Compliance with cGMPs
- Knowledgeable in quality control standards, MSDS, SOPs, CAPAs, and Deviations
- Excellent communication skills
- Proficient in Spanish and English
- Exceptional work ethics
- · Time management
- Strong interpersonal skills
- Customer service-oriented
- Production scheduling familiarity
- Microsoft Office applications (Excel, Word, Power Point), Internet, and office equipment.

### Accomplishments

- Trained new Coating Scientists on cGMP production of drug manufactured
- Conducted over 20 job Interviews, hired and coached new employees
- Revised Standard Operating Procedures
- Opened and closed deviations with Corrective Action Preventative Actions
- Selected to be part of the film Insulin project and pioneer in Operator Care
- Took it upon myself to order supplies needed to improve employees working conditions
- Highly respectable and reliable
- Determined and always willing to help others
- Great team player
- Enjoy presenting new and more efficient ideas to improved a process

#### Experience

# Coating Scientist

March 2011 to Current Imerys i1/4 Taos County, NM

- Committed in following current good manufacturing practices, good documentation practices and standard operating procedures to be in compliance with FDA and DEA regulations
- Specialist in weighing, delumping, mixing, coating and slitting pharmaceutical products
- Perform analytical Checks to ensure that our products are safe and maintain high quality standards
- Revised standard operating procedures, production batch records and log books
- Assisted Quality Control with deviations and corrective action preventative action by bringing backlog up to date
- Experience with ADP and Web Time tracking
- Excellent work ethics, high standards and take pride in all I do

#### Production Operator/Production Coordinator

October 2006 to November 2010 Avalon Health Care Group i1/4 Eugene, OR

- Specialist in blending, filler, labeler, case packer, Hi-Cone, palletizer and depalletizer of Gatorade/Propel product. Never scrapped a batch I made.
- Performed chemical, analytical, chlorine, code/date, label, case and pallet checks to ensure quality of product
- Followed standard operating procedures, good manufacturing practices and good documentation practices
- Certified in Blending, Filler and Palletizer
- Was backup Team Leader
- Experience with Autonomous Maintenance, one point lessons, kaizens, and Health, Safety and Environmental
- As a production coordinator, I made sure the production lines were staffed accordingly, managed the over time, lay offs, reallocations and temporary staffing when needed in a fare manner.
- Performed Finished Goods Reconciliations at the end of every shift, to ensure inventory compliance utilizing SAP program
- Worked hand in hand with Human Resources
- · Member of the Diversity and Inclusion committee and volunteered in planning company events

## CNA Coordinator

December 2002 to May 2005 Hospice Of The Valley i1/4 City, STATE

• Pioneer as a CNA Coordinator

- Expertly coordinated approximately 40 Certified Nursing Assistants
- Reviewed patient's medical file, treatments, conditions, location and caregiver demands prior to assigning case to Certified Nursing Assistant
- Maintained up-to-date weekly schedules with all pertinent information
- Participated in ICC meetings and weekly Certified nursing assistant training
- Served as liaison between case managers, Certified Nursing Assistant, patient and caregivers
- Translated for Spanish speaking only caregivers
- Updated medical records in the data system
- Maintained supply inventory and continuously met budget requirements

#### Education

 $\mbox{GED}$  : General Education , 2011 Portage Adult Education il/4 City , State , USA Languages

Fluent in Spanish & English (written and orally).

## Skills

- Experience in Production and Manufacturing field
- Excellent communication and interpersonal skills
- Great work ethics
- Responsible and result driven
- Team player
- Take pride in my work and challenge myself to do better each day
- Computer savvy

# Additional Information

• Illinois Real Estate Agent, 1995